Nano Banana 2 just dropped and yes, it's
more fresh than these bananas with
upgrades to visual fidelity, advanced
world knowledge, and supposedly accurate
label text rendering. It should also
have stronger instruction following and
subject consistency with up to five
characters. And at the end of this
video, I'm going to test the subject
consistency with myself as the subject.
And I actually found another AI image
model that maybe does it even better
than Nano Banana 2. Welcome back to the
channel. And if you're new here, my name
is Thomas and I make videos about AI
product photography. You're probably
thinking, didn't we already get Nano
Banana 2? And yes, the naming here of
the models is very confusing. So,
basically, Nanobanana 2 has all the
capabilities of Nanobanana Pro with a
few upgrades and it's based on Gemini
3.1 Flash, which means it's also much
faster than Nano Banana Pro. You can of
course use it in the Gemini app itself,
but I need images without a watermark
and in 4K quality. So that's why I'm
using it over at Hicksfield AI where you
can get the 4K quality and no watermark
and you have access to all the different
image models and video models available.
Hicksfield were kind enough to sponsor
this video and if you want to check them
out, there's a link in the description
below. As a product photographer, the
most important thing I wanted to test
and compare was the text rendering
capabilities. So, we're going to take it
from easy to extreme. Really stress
testing the model and seeing if there's
improvements and how does it compare to
Nano Banana Pro. I started out with this
simple iPhone image of the moisturizing
product. And for this one, I wanted
contrasting colors and just a soft
element. So, I thought about the parrots
soft feathers. And this is the result we
got. For this one, the result is
basically perfect. The parrot is very
high quality and detailed. The text
rendering is perfect with no errors
whatsoever. And if you compare it to
Nanob Banana Pro, the quality is on the
same level, but it's just much faster.
For the next example, we're going to
make it even harder for the model. This
is a simple iPhone photo of a bottle
with a really complicated label with
different graphic elements and text
elements in different placements, which
can really trip up the AI models. But
using the iPhone image along with this
prompt, we get this result. And here I
have to say, I really didn't expect it
to get it this spoton. There's basically
no errors in the text or the graphics.
Everything is just perfect. But we can't
let Nano Banana 2 get away that easily.
So I gave it this prompt with the
shampoo bottle image. And this is the
result we got. This prompt was really
made to break the model on the text
rendering because placing three bottles
in a side position like this will make
it really hard for it to generate every
single detail. Right? But considering
that we started only with a shitty
iPhone image of the bottle and this is
the accuracy and result is very very
impressive. And again the same theme as
before. Nano Banana 2 and Nano Banana
Pro both performed quite on the same
level. Nano Banana 2 is just faster. For
the hint example, I wanted to see if it
can handle the microscopic text on the
label itself and how it would place the
tagline in the advertisement. And using
this image and this prompt, we got this
result. And as expected, the microscopic
text on the label isn't quite right. But
overall, this is a very good result with
the tagline being integrated into the
design quite well. Actually, comparing
this to the result from Nanobanana Pro
using the exact same image and the exact
same prompt, the tagline isn't
integrated into the design as well in my
opinion, and it also has the same small
errors of the microscopic text on the
label. So far, Nano Banana 2 has handled
everything pretty well in my opinion,
but now we're going to crank it up a
notch and really push it to the limit
with the text and graphical rendering
and the subject consistency. And to do
this, I created my own burger chain
called Banana Burgers with these designs
off the package and this exact chicken
burger. First, I wanted to see if it can
handle this harsh flash burger product
photo style while keeping the burger
exactly accurate to the reference and
the graphics and the logo on the
branding itself as well. And I have to
say, the marketing team at Banana
Burgers must be proud of this image
because everything was kept perfectly
accurate with the graphics, the text,
and the details of the burger itself.
And actually, let me know what you think
about this using AI for food
photography. Because when I was thinking
about it first, my first reaction was
that's not good. I want to have a
picture of the real food. But then
again, if you think about burger
commercials, when do the burgers
actually look like in the commercial
itself? So, where does the line go? Give
me your thoughts in the comment section
below. But moving on and cranking up the
difficulty even more for Nano Banana 2.
I wanted to create like a hero billboard
shot of a hand holding the exact chicken
burger with towers of burger boxes
around it. And this was the prompt I
used along with these reference images.
And this is the result we got. And
again, looking at all the details of the
Banana Burger branding, I have to say
that it just made a really good job
here. I mean, I only gave it a couple of
simple reference images of the branding.
In this case, I would actually say that
Nano Banana 2 handled it better than
Nanobanana Pro, but if you generate a
couple of times, I think the results are
quite similar. Next up, we're going to
test the character consistency that was
supposed to have an upgrade in Nano
Banana 2. And to do that, I created
these five characters that's going to go
on a dinner date at Banana Burgers. And
we're going to see how well it can keep
both the object consistency, branding,
and character consistency of five
characters at the same time. And using
these reference images and this prompt,
this is the result we got. When it comes
to character consistency and object
consistency in this image, I have to
give props to Nanob Banana 2. It got all
the characters spoton and the branding
and details of the burgers is also
accurate. The only question I have is
how is this guy eating three burgers for
himself and he haven't even touched his
banana fries. Now, that's of course
impressive, but what if you don't have a
professional quality character sheet
with different angles, but only have
iPhone images of your character that you
want to use in your generation? If we
try generating images of myself using
just iPhone images as references, you
can see that the results are not quite
accurate and not consistent across
images at all. But this is where
Hicksfield's own image model, Soul 2,
that they just launched, actually
performs better than Nano Banana 2.
Because in Soul 2, you can create a Soul
ID character of yourself, where you can
upload up to 80 images from different
angles that will then create a
consistent character that you can use
across generations just by tagging it in
the prompt itself. And as you can see
from these examples, the accuracy of me
in these images is night and day
compared to the examples from Nano
Banana 2 and Nano Banana Pro. But the
real superpowers are enabled when you
combine the character consistency
capabilities of Soul 2 with the editing
capabilities of Nano Banana, which makes
it possible to create consistent
characters wearing your products, for
example. And not only can you get
consistent characters, but you can use
the hex color feature to also get
consistent colors through different
images with the character. So here I
created this image of me standing in
front of the metro and I used that image
as the base image to get the color
palette for the rest of the images that
I generated. Then when I had the base
images with the generic clothing, I
could just use the Nanobanana Pro inpar
brands that I created. And just like
that, we had a consistent streetear
photo shoot with me as the model and the
colors being the exact same across all
images, making them look like they
belong together. And you can test out
both the Soul ID character feature and
Nano Banana 2 from the link in the
description below. And if you want
access to all the prompts and examples I
showed you in this video, make sure to
join my free school community. It's a
place where I will be uploading all my
prompts from my videos. And there's also
a community of amazing people excited
about AI where we can share knowledge
and resources. So if that sounds like
something that you are interested in,
make sure to check out the link below.
So to summarize Nano Banana 2, it seems
like it's not a game-changing
groundbreaking update. It's a welcome
update with faster generations at the
same quality and capabilities of Nano
Banana Pro. If you like this type of
content, make sure to subscribe. And
next week there might be a seed dance 2
video coming.